Eamon Grennan papers, 1964-2010
Emory University
- Writings by Grennan, 1962-2010, Series 2; Boxes 3 - 53; BV 1 - 3
  - Poetry, 1962-2010, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 3 - 39
    - Uncollected poetry, circa 1960s-2010, Subseries 2.1b; Boxes 21 - 31
      - "Saturday Afternoon in the Village" (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - "Saving" (Box 28, Folder 34)
      - "Scarab" (Box 28, Folder 35)
      - "Sea and Smoke" [Variant titles: "Start with Sea and Smoke" and "Start"] (Box 28, Folder 36)
      - "Sea Creatures" (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - "Seafarer" (Box 28, Folder 38)
      - "Search" (Box 28, Folder 39)
      - "Search Party" (Box 28, Folder 40)
      - "Seasonal" (Box 28, Folder 41)
      - "Seated Figure" (Box 28, Folder 42)
      - "See How Deep the River Is" (Box 28, Folder 43)
      - "Self Portrait" (Box 28, Folder 44)
      - "Sense of Place" [Variant titles: "A Sense of Place" and "Living Alone"] (Box 28, Folder 45)
      - "Sentenced" (Box 28, Folder 46)
      - "Sentences" (Box 28, Folder 47)
      - "September" (Box 28, Folder 48)
      - "September Air" (Box 28, Folder 49)
      - "September First" (Box 28, Folder 50)
      - "Setting Off" (Box 28, Folder 51)
      - "Seven A.M." (Box 28, Folder 52)
      - "Sewer Watch" (Box 28, Folder 53)
      - "Shades of Summer" (Box 28, Folder 54)
      - "Shadows" (Box 28, Folder 55)
      - "Shape Up" (Box 28, Folder 56)
      - "Shapes" (Box 28, Folder 57)
      - "She" [Also includes untitled poem] (Box 28, Folder 58)
      - "Shoreline After Storm [Variant titles: "Shore After Storm," "After the Storms of Winter," and "Renvyle Beach"] (Box 28, Folder 59)
      - "A Short History of Hands" (Box 28, Folder 60)
      - "Sickness and Health" (Box 28, Folder 61)
      - "Sighting" (Box 28, Folder 62)
      - "Sign Language" (Box 28, Folder 63)
      - "Signs" (Box 28, Folder 64)
      - "Silent Pictures" (Box 28, Folder 65)
      - "Silk" [Variant title: "Silkworms"] (Box 28, Folder 66)
      - "Simon Says" (Box 28, Folder 67)
      - "Singing Women" (Box 28, Folder 68)
      - "Sitter, Renvyle" (Box 28, Folder 69)
      - "Sitting in a Field on a Windy Day" (Box 28, Folder 70)
      - "Sitting with My Sleeping Father" (Box 28, Folder 71)
      - "Sketches" (Box 28, Folder 72)
      - "Skull" (Box 28, Folder 73)
      - "Small Birds Big Wind" (Box 28, Folder 74)
      - "Small Sketch by Rembrandt" (Box 28, Folder 75)
      - "Small Talk" (Box 28, Folder 76)
      - "Snails" (Box 28, Folder 77)
      - "Snatches" [Includes untitled fragment] (Box 28, Folder 78)
      - "Snowdrops" (Box 28, Folder 79)
      - "Solitaire" (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - "Some Rime Not Quite Riche for Clarke" (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - "Something in the Water" (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - "Somewhere in Ireland" [Variant titles: "What Happens Here," "In the Balance," and "Losses"] (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - "Son Sleeping" (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - "Song" (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - "Song" (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - "Song for a Stormy Day" (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - "A Song for Kira Maeve Kitzinger Grennan Who's Three" (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - "Song of Circumstance" (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - "Sonnet with Nothing to Say" (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - "Sons et Lumieres: December" (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - "Sounding Out" (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - "Squall" (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - "Span" (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - "Special Effects" (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - "Spring" (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - "The Spring" [Also includes "The Couple"] (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - "Spring and Kira" (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - "Spring in America" (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - "St. Patrick's Hospital" (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - "Start of Spring" (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - "Starting the Poem" [Variant title: "Starting a Poem"] (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - "Stays" (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - "Steady As She Goes" (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - "Stepping into Winter" [Variant title: "Winterblitz"] (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - "Still Life: Three Mexican Figures on Nancy Stover's Painting" [Variant title: "Painting by Nancy Stover"] (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - "Still Life with Father" (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - "Still Life with Skeleton and Shoes" (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - "Stillness" (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - "Stirrings" (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - "Stop on the Coast Road" (Box 29, Folder 32)
      - "Stop-Over in London" (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - "Storm" (Box 29, Folder 34)
      - "Storm" (Box 29, Folder 35)
      - "Story" [Variant title: "Rumpelstiltskin"] (Box 29, Folder 36)
      - "Striking Gold" (Box 29, Folder 37)
      - "Such a State" [Variant title: "Out Here"] (Box 29, Folder 38)
      - "Such Sights" (Box 29, Folder 39)
      - "Sudden Spring" (Box 29, Folder 40)
      - "A Summing-Up" [Variant title: "Summing-Up"] (Box 29, Folder 41)
      - "Sun Strokes" (Box 29, Folder 42)
      - "Sunday Evening" (Box 29, Folder 43)
      - "Sunlight, Starlings, Moles" (Box 29, Folder 44)
      - "Sunrise" (Box 29, Folder 45)
      - "Sunset, Trolley, Swans" (Box 29, Folder 46)
      - "Surely the Silence" (Box 29, Folder 47)
      - "Survivor" [Also includes "House Work"] (Box 29, Folder 48)
      - "Swift" (Box 29, Folder 49)
      - "Swimming" [Variant title: "Taking Off"] (Box 29, Folder 50)
      - "Taking Off" (Box 29, Folder 51)
      - "Tapdance" (Box 29, Folder 52)
      - "Taste" (Box 29, Folder 53)
      - "Teaching Birds" (Box 29, Folder 54)
      - "Telling Time" [Variant title: "Rendezvous A Narrative"] (Box 29, Folder 55)
      - "Tenth Wedding Anniversary" (Box 29, Folder 56)
      - "That Not Impossible" [sic] (Box 29, Folder 57)
      - "Things are Happening" (Box 29, Folder 58)
      - "Three at Fifty" [Variant titles: "For my 50th Birthday" and "Signs"] (Box 29, Folder 59)
      - "Three Images for St. Valentine's Day" (Box 29, Folder 60)
      - "Three in a Garden" (Box 29, Folder 61)
      - "Three in the Light" (Box 29, Folder 62)
      - "Three in the Morning" [Variant titles: "From a Sketchbook," "Three A.M.," "Mother-to-Be," "Peace," "Strawberries," "Waving Goodbye," "Poem in October," "Our Way," "Kira Waking," "Iris," "She Meets Keats," "She Goes for a Walk," and "Playing"] (Folder 63)
      - "Three Men Cleaning a Sewer" (Box 29, Folder 64)
      - "Threshold Children" [Variant titles: "Thresholds" and "For Kate and Conor, a Kind of Letter"] (Box 29, Folder 65)
      - "Thresholding" (Box 29, Folder 66)
      - "This and That" (Box 29, Folder 67)
      - "This Happened" (Box 29, Folder 68)
      - "This Morning" (Box 29, Folder 69)
      - "Tide" [Variant title: "On a Strand in North Dublin"] (Box 29, Folder 70)
      - "Tight Corner" (Box 29, Folder 71)
      - "Tight Rope Artist" (Box 29, Folder 72)
      - "Time for a Change" (Box 29, Folder 73)
      - "Timely" [Variant title: "Timely Reminders"] (Box 29, Folder 74)
      - "To Charlie, on His 60th Birthday" (Box 29, Folder 75)
      - "To My Wife" (Box 29, Folder 76)
      - "To Silvia" (Box 29, Folder 77)
      - "To the Mirror by the Door in Going" (Box 29, Folder 78)
      - "To the Sparrow When It Snows" (Box 29, Folder 79)
      - "To the Unborn" (Box 29, Folder 80)
      - "Today Bright Sunlight" (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - "Tongued" (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - "The Torn Spiderweb" (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - "Track" (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - "Tracks" (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - "Tracks" (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - "Traditional Moment" (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - "Train Ride with Kira" [Variant title: "Train Ride"] (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - "Translations" (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - "The Trap" (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - "Tree and Bird" (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - "Tree. Falling." (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - "Tree Time" [Variant title: "The Day After Tomorrow"] (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - "Trees" [Variant title: "Thinking Trees"] (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - "Trees: The Old Story" (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - "Trial in Spring" (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - "Tully High Road, Dusk" [See Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Words"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Tully High Road, Going Home" (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - "Tuning Up" (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - "Two Hangovers" (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - "Two Photographs" (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - "Two Views at Dusk" (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - "Two Views from Middle Age" [Variant titles: "Boys of Summer" and "Girl Reading"] (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - "Two Weeks Away" (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - "Unnatural Act" (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - Untitled poems and fragments (Box 30, Folder 25)
      - "Useless Lines for the Imprisoned Doctor, Anatoly Koryagin" (Box 30, Folder 26)
      - "Vanishing Point" (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - "Vanishing Points" (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - "Vermeer's Soldier and Girl" (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - "View" (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - "Village Funeral" (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - "Visit" (Box 30, Folder 32)
      - "The Visit" (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - "Visiting Home" (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - "Visiting Seattle" (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - "Visitor" (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - "Waiting" (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - "Waiting for the Snow to Start" (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - "Waiting Room" [Variant title: "Around Nothing a Breathing"] (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - "Waking" [Variant titles: "In the Nature of Things," "Coming To," and "A Waking"] (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - "Waking Alone" (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - "Waking Thoughts" (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - "Walk" (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - "Walk" (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - "Walk at Dawn, New Hampshire" (Box 30, Folder 45)
      - "Walk Music" (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - "Walker" (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - "Walks" (Box 30, Folder 48)
      - "Wall Hanging" [Variant titles: "In a Season of Change" and "Balancing Act"] (Box 30, Folder 49)
      - "War Photo" [Variant title: "Photo"] (Box 30, Folder 50)
      - "Watercolour in Autumn" (Box 30, Folder 51)
      - "Waterfall" (Box 30, Folder 52)
      - "The Way and the Light" (Box 30, Folder 53)
      - "Way In, Way Out" (Box 30, Folder 54)
      - "Wayfaring" (Box 30, Folder 55)
      - "Weathering" (Box 30, Folder 56)
      - "Weathering It" (Box 30, Folder 57)
      - "Weathery" (Box 30, Folder 58)
      - "Whale Without Sense of Direction" (Box 30, Folder 59)
      - "What Happens" (Box 30, Folder 60)
      - "What October Offers" (Box 30, Folder 61)
      - "What Song?" (Box 30, Folder 62)
      - "What the Hands Do" (Box 30, Folder 63)
      - "What You Learn in Translation" [Variant title: "The Pleasures of Translation or Sex in Translation: The First Lesson"] (Box 30, Folder 64)
      - "What's Going On" (Box 30, Folder 65)
      - "Wheelbarrow" (Box 30, Folder 66)
      - "When?" (Box 30, Folder 67)
      - "When Letters Arrive" (Box 30, Folder 68)
      - "Where the Road Ends" (Box 30, Folder 69)
      - "The Whole Story or Sounds Good to Me" (Box 30, Folder 70)
      - "Widow Garden" (Box 30, Folder 71)
      - "Widowhood Visited" (Box 30, Folder 72)
      - "Wife's Kitchen Picture" (Box 30, Folder 73)
      - "Window" (Box 30, Folder 74)
      - "Window Bird" (Box 30, Folder 75)
      - "Window Image" (Box 30, Folder 76)
      - "Window Weather" (Box 30, Folder 77)
      - "Windwalking" (Box 30, Folder 78)
      - "Wings" (Box 30, Folder 79)
      - "Winter Bees" (Box 30, Folder 80)
      - "Wintereise" [Variant title: "Contingencies"] (Box 30, Folder 81)
      - "With the Left Hand of January" (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - "With Youngest Daughter at Parent's Grave" [Variant titles: "With My Youngest Daughter at the Grave of My Parents," "With My Daughter at the Grave of My Parents," "With Youngest Daughter," and "Grave"] [Also includes "Neighbour"] (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - "Woman with Cut Flowers" [Variant titles: "Cut Flowers" and "A Bunch of Cut Flowers"] (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - "Women's Voices" [Variant title: "Some Women's Voices I Have Known] (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - "Woodwalk" (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - "Word" (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - "A Word for the Birds" (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - "Words" [Also includes "Tully High Road, Dusk"] (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - "Words" [Variant title: "The Way Words"] (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - "World" (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - "The World as Constant Occasion" (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - "World Views" (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - "World We Live In" (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - "Wren at Window" (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - "Writing" (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - "Yellowthroat in October" (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Chronological poetry drafts, 1962-2008, Subseries 2.1c; Boxes 32 - 39
      The subseries contains drafts of poems arranged chronologically by Grennan from 1962-2008. Grennan's original arrangement has been preserved, with the exception that poems have been arranged alphabetically within each folder. The dates on folders often overlap, such that a poem might appear in multiple folders within a given date range. This subseries, while not a comprehensive collection of all of Grennan's poems, reveals the scope of his work throughout his career.
      The poems in this subseries might also duplicate poems located in Subseries 2.1a: Collected poetry and Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry.
      Arranged in chronological order, with poems arranged alphabetically within each folder.
      - 1962-1964, poem fragments (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - 1962-1964, untitled poems (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - 1962-1964, A-L (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - 1962-1964, O-V (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - 1980 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - 1983-1986 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - 1984, poem fragments (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - 1984, untitled poems (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - 1984, B-L (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - 1984, M-W (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - 1984-1989 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Mid-1980s, untitled poems (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Mid-1980s, A-L (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Mid-1980s, M-W (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - 1985, untitled poems (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - 1985, A-G (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - 1985, H-R (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - 1985, S-W (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - 1986, untitled poem (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - 1986, poem fragment (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - 1986, A-W (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - 1987-1988, poem fragments (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - 1987-1988, untitled poems (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - 1987-1988, 362-J (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - 1987-1988, L-S (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - 1987-1988, T-W (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - 1996-2001, untitled poem (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - 1996-2001, A-G (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - 1996-2001, H-O (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - 1996-2001, P-T (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - 1996-2001, V-W (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - 1997 January, A-L (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - 1997 January, M-W (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - 1997 Summer, untitled poems (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - 1997 Summer, A-W (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - 1997-1999, untitled poems (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - 1997-1999, A-D (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - 1997-1999, E-I (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - 1997-1999, J-Q (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - 1997-1999, R-V (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - 1997-1999, W (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - 1999 Summer [early revisions], untitled poem (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - 1999 Summer [early revisions], poem fragment (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - 1999 Summer [early revisions], A-L (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - 1999 Summer [early revisions], M-W (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - 2001, third revision (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - 2001 January, third revision (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - 2001 February, third revision (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - 2001 March, third revision (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - 2001 April, third revision (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - 2001 May, third revision (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - 2001 June, third revision (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - 2001 July, third revision (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - 2001 August, third revision (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - 2001 September, third revision (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - 2001 October, third revision (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 2001 November, third revision (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 2001 December, third revision (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - 2001 fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - 2001 January, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - 2001 February, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - 2001 March, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - 2001 April, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - 2001 May, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - 2001 June, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - 2001 July, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - 2001 August, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - 2001 September, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - 2001 October, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - 2001 November, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - 2001 December, fifth revision (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - 2001-2005, A-I (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - 2001-2005, J-Y (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - 2001-2005, revisions [Summer 2005] (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - 2001-2005, revisions [Summer 2005] (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - 2001-2006 (Box 37, Folder 18)
      - 2002-2004, A-L (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - 2002-2004, M-Y (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - 2006 June-September [revised 2007] (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - 2006 Spring and Fall (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - 2006 October-2008 November, A-K (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - 2006 October-2008 November, L-W (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - 2006 October-2008 November, second revision [September-October 2008] (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - 2006 October-2008 November, third revision [November 2008] (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - 2006 October-2008 November, fourth and fifth revisions, A-R (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - 2006 October-2008 November, fourth and fifth revisions, S-Y (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Prose, 1964-2010, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 40 - 41; BV 1
    The subseries consists of Grennan's prose writings from 1964-2010. Some of Grennan's early writings can be found in this subseries, including several short stories that he wrote while in Italy in 1964, numerous academic papers he wrote while a student at Harvard University in the 1960s, and his doctoral dissertation. Also included are reviews of books, introductions for readings by other authors, and various articles, essays, and other prose pieces.
    - Articles, essays, and other prose
    - "Atlanta Angry," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - "Autobiographical Note," published in World Authors series, no date (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "The Call," convocation address, Vassar College, April 28, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Clarke and Kavanagh: Irish Poetic Identity after Yeats," typescript draft, November 29, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Dual Characterization: A Note on Chaucer's Use of 'But' in the Portrait of the Parson," typescript, published in The Chaucer Review, Winter 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Elegy," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Equilibrist," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Essay for First Loves: Poets Introduce the Essential Poems that Captivated and Inspired Them, typescript drafts, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Essay on Irish and American literary elements, published in Metre, Autumn 1997 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Family Group," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "Foreword" to The Road to Deadman Cove by George Anthony, unpublished, circa 1976 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "Garden," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - "Johnson and Vaughan," typescript draft, published in The Irish Times, November 1983 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Light" [Variant title: "Witness the Light"], typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "Memorial Minute for James Day," by Grennan, Robert Brown, Robert DeMaria, Rachel Kitzinger, Ben Kohl, and Robert Pounder, typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - "Narcissus Nub," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "Orpheus Exposed," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - "Outing," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - "'Prologues to What Is Possible': Coming to (Some) Terms with Stevens," published in Green Mountain Review, winter 2009 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "Renvyle Garden," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "Richard Hugo," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - "Seven Scraps to Start the Year With," typescript draft, January 7, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - "'A Slight Companionable Ghost:' Trying to Catch Sight of Yeats's Mother," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "A Sort of Portrait of Renvyle," typescript draft, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - "Soul Music in Yeats and Kavanagh," typescript and manuscript drafts and notes, no date (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - "Squirrel," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - "Still Life," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - "Sunset, Trolley, Swans," typescript drafts, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - "Tarot or Not Tarot," typescript draft, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - "Trimming," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - "Unacquainted with the Night," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - "Unpacking," typescript draft, no date (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Untitled essay, typescript, no date (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - "What I Heard There," essay, published in Metre, Spring/Summer 2000 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - "Women's Speech in Shakespeare," bibliographic material, no date (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - "Women's Speech in Shakespeare," manuscript drafts [1 of 2], no date (Box 40, Folder 36)
    - "Women's Speech in Shakespeare," manuscript drafts [2 of 2], no date (Box 40, Folder 37)
    - "Women's Speech in Shakespeare," notes, no date (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - "Women's Speech in Shakespeare," partial manuscript and typescript drafts, no date (Box 40, Folder 39)
    - Introductions for readings by others
    - Asekoff, Louis, no date (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Bidart, Frank, Villanova Literary Festival, Villanova University, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Carey, Peter, no date (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Clampitt, Amy, no date (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Collins, Billy, Elizabeth Bishop Annual Poetry Reading, Vassar College, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Delanty, Greg, Vassar College, no date (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Dunn, Douglas and Michael Longley, no date (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Duncan, Paul, Derek Mahon, and Paul Muldoon, no date (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Gibson, Margaret, no date (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Groarke, Vona, 5th Annual Irish Poetry Reading in Memory of Michael Durkan, Swarthmore College, April 2002 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Elizabeth Bishop Annual Poetry Reading, Vassar College, no date (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Heaney, Seamus, James Joyce Centennial Celebration, Vassar College, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Komunyakaa, Yusef, Elizabeth Bishop Annual Poetry Reading, Vassar College, circa 2004 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Longley, Michael, no date (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Longley, Michael and John McGahern, no date (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - MacCarthy, Catherine, Ireland House, New York University, no date (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - McGahern, John, no date (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Olds, Sharon, Elizabeth Bishop Annual Poetry Reading, Vassar College, no date (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Palmer, Michael, no date (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Tillinghast, Richard, no date (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Yeats, Michael and John Montague, Yeats and Ireland event commemorating W.B. Yeats, Vassar College, April 27, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Reviews
    - "American Breath, American Bone," review of Selected Poems by Philip Levine and Selected Poems by Galway Kinnell, no date (Box 41, Folder 22)